<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://klassmates.us///feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://klassmates.us///feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://klassmates.us///" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-02T13:14:21+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///</id><title type="html">Koha Klassmates</title><subtitle>A fre service for library classrooms from ByWater Solutions</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Koha Klassmates 18.11 Upgrade</title><link href="http://klassmates.us///blog/klassmates-upgrade/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Koha Klassmates 18.11 Upgrade" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///blog/klassmates-upgrade</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://klassmates.us///blog/klassmates-upgrade/">&lt;p&gt;All Klassmates systems were upgraded to 18.11 this past weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the Koha Community 18.11 Release here: https://koha-community.org/koha-18-11-release/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And see highlights with notes and videos on the ByWater Solutions’ Site and all 18.11 tutorials: https://bywatersolutions.com/education?q=18.11&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember to visit the ByWater Solutions website for all new tutorials on Koha for you and your students. We have all tutorial videos on our YouTube channel as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">We hope all of you are enjoying your Klassmates System. Remember to visit the ByWater Solutions website for all new tutorials on Koha for you and your students. We have all tutorial videos on our youtube channel as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SSL Certificates for all Klassmates Sites</title><link href="http://klassmates.us///blog/ssl/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SSL Certificates for all Klassmates Sites" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///blog/ssl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://klassmates.us///blog/ssl/">&lt;p&gt;We hope all of you are enjoying your Klassmates System. Remember to visit the ByWater Solutions website for all new tutorials on Koha for you and your students. We have all tutorial videos on our youtube channel as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to let you know about an update to your site. All of you may notice that web browsers are becoming much more “vocal” about warning users when they connect to unsecured websites, that is, sites not protected with a SSL certificate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In next week or so, we will be implementing SSL on all sites hosted on the Klassmates system. We will be enabling automatic redirection from http to https. You will not need to do anything on your side, we just want you to be aware this is coming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for sharing the enthusiasm for Koha with your class!&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">We hope all of you are enjoying your Klassmates System. Remember to visit the ByWater Solutions website for all new tutorials on Koha for you and your students. We have all tutorial videos on our youtube channel as well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Koha Klassmates Adopted in 20 Library Schools Nationwide</title><link href="http://klassmates.us///blog/twenty-libraries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Koha Klassmates Adopted in 20 Library Schools Nationwide" /><published>2016-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///blog/twenty-libraries</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://klassmates.us///blog/twenty-libraries/">&lt;p&gt;The Koha Klassmates program is dedicated to providing free hosted Koha installations for library schools in the US for the purposes of teaching and learning about integrated library systems and open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following library schools are using Koha Klassmates in at least one class (many in multiple):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;College of DuPage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dominican University&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IUPUI School of Informatics, Dept of Library and Information Science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kent State University, SLIS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mohawk College&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plymouth State University&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red River College&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robert Gordon University&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rutgers University&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Texas Woman’s University&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Maryland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Missouri-Columbia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Nebraska Omaha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of North Texas College of Information&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Pitt LIS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of South Carolina School of Library and Information Science&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Washington Information School&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Wisconsin-Madison, School of Library and Information Studies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wayne State University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William Helling, Instructor at IUPUI, spoke of his class’s experience with Klassmates so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My LIS graduate course, Library Systems, is going very well, and the Koha library we created is the cornerstone of the class that we build upon every week. Our library is not without blemishes, of course (as in real life!), but it was constructed from the ground up, from nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian Rountree, MLIS, Instructor at Red River College spoke of his plans for Klassmates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have found it very helpful to have the students practice using as many different library programs as I can find. It brings ‘real life’ to the classroom activities and assignments. It provides skills they can use when at their practicum sites. It is a bonus when they can say at an interview that they are familiar with certain products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicole C. Engard, Vice President of Community Outreach, commented on the quick success of Klassmates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m so excited to see so many instructors using Koha in their classes. When I was in library school I didn’t have this opportunity and strongly believe that using a full ILS in a classroom setting makes a huge difference when students enter the work force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha-klassmates&quot;&gt;About Koha Klassmates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha Klassmates is a service of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com&quot;&gt;ByWater Solutions&lt;/a&gt;, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support. This service offers free hosted installations of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org&quot;&gt;Koha Open Source ILS&lt;/a&gt; to library school instructors for use in their classrooms. Using this service library school students can learn what it means to use a real ILS before entering the workforce. For more information or to sign up please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://klassmates.us&quot;&gt;http://klassmates.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha&quot;&gt;About Koha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha is the first open-source Integrated Library System (ILS). In use worldwide, its development is steered by a growing community of libraries collaborating to achieve their technology goals. Koha’s impressive feature set continues to evolve and expand to meet the needs of its user base. It includes modules for circulation, cataloging, acquisitions, serials, reserves, patron management, branch relationships, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koha’s OPAC, circulation, management and self-checkout interfaces are all based on standards-compliant World Wide Web technologies–XHTML, CSS and Javascript–making Koha a truly platform-independent solution. Koha is distributed under the open-source General Public License (GPL). For more information about Koha, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org/&quot;&gt;http://koha-community.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-bywater-solutions&quot;&gt;About ByWater Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ByWater Solutions is a full service, high quality support and implementation company dedicated to providing libraries with a lower cost, more advanced level of support for their ILS than a traditional proprietary solution can offer. ByWater Solutions has a proven track record in first rate Koha implementation and support with library systems of all sizes. Our highly ranked, comprehensive support is what sets our company apart from any other vendor in the industry. Partnering with ByWater Solutions to support Koha not only lowers the cost of implementing and maintaining an ILS, but more importantly empowers libraries by giving them the flexibility and freedom they deserve. For more information please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com/&quot;&gt;https://bywatersolutions.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">ByWater Solutions, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support, announced today that since its roll out six months ago, 20 library schools are now using the Koha Klassmates program nationwide.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IUPUI School of Informatics to use Koha Klassmates</title><link href="http://klassmates.us///blog/iupui/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IUPUI School of Informatics to use Koha Klassmates" /><published>2015-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///blog/iupui</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://klassmates.us///blog/iupui/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;iupui-school-of-informatics-to-use-koha-klassmates&quot;&gt;IUPUI School of Informatics to use Koha Klassmates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;William Helling, Ph.D., Lecturer, Library and Information Science spoke of his plans for his students using Klassmates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have been a systems librarian for more than 15 years, and I have taught library systems for Indiana University (IU and IUPUI) for the same amount of time. As a librarian, I have always regretted that so many of my fellow staff members were completely unfamiliar with their own ILS. These staff members were either not encouraged to look beyond their restricted duties or were never even allowed to use the different modules that make up a typical ILS. As a result, I discovered that most librarians were unaware of how an ILS worked and what it could do for them. As a result, I have always been determined to teach my library systems courses using as many hand-on tools as possible. ByWater Solutions’ Koha Klassmates program allows me to do that. With the Klassmates program, my graduate library science students will have staff access to the major ILS modules (Circulation, Cataloging, Serials, Acquisitions, OPAC) that they will eventually deal with in their future careers. We can build a library, determine polices, catalog items, and circulate. We can also work with the administration of the ILS, run reports, and learn to adjust our library. ByWater Solutions’ Koha Klassmates program allows me to give students invaluable experience in a modern and fully-functional ILS — experience that will benefit them as well as the institutions for which they eventually work. I spring 2016 I will use Koha Klassmates in my IUPUI S554 class Library Systems as well as my S503 Organization and Representation of Knowledge and Information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha-klassmates&quot;&gt;About Koha Klassmates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha Klassmates is a service of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com&quot;&gt;ByWater Solutions&lt;/a&gt;, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support. This service offers free hosted installations of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org&quot;&gt;Koha Open Source ILS&lt;/a&gt; to library school instructors for use in their classrooms. Using this service library school students can learn what it means to use a real ILS before entering the workforce. For more information or to sign up please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://klassmates.us&quot;&gt;http://klassmates.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha&quot;&gt;About Koha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha is the first open-source Integrated Library System (ILS). In use worldwide, its development is steered by a growing community of libraries collaborating to achieve their technology goals. Koha’s impressive feature set continues to evolve and expand to meet the needs of its user base. It includes modules for circulation, cataloging, acquisitions, serials, reserves, patron management, branch relationships, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koha’s OPAC, circulation, management and self-checkout interfaces are all based on standards-compliant World Wide Web technologies–XHTML, CSS and Javascript–making Koha a truly platform-independent solution. Koha is distributed under the open-source General Public License (GPL). For more information about Koha, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org/&quot;&gt;http://koha-community.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-bywater-solutions&quot;&gt;About ByWater Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ByWater Solutions is a full service, high quality support and implementation company dedicated to providing libraries with a lower cost, more advanced level of support for their ILS than a traditional proprietary solution can offer. ByWater Solutions has a proven track record in first rate Koha implementation and support with library systems of all sizes. Our highly ranked, comprehensive support is what sets our company apart from any other vendor in the industry. Partnering with ByWater Solutions to support Koha not only lowers the cost of implementing and maintaining an ILS, but more importantly empowers libraries by giving them the flexibility and freedom they deserve. For more information please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com/&quot;&gt;https://bywatersolutions.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">ByWater Solutions, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support, is happy to announce that the more than 20 students enrolled in ‘Library Systems’ and ‘Organization and Representation of Knowledge and Information’ classes at the Indiana University–Purdue University Indianapolis School of Informatics and Computing, and will be using Koha through the Klassmates (http://klassmates.us) program.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Red River College using Koha Klassmates</title><link href="http://klassmates.us///blog/red-river-college/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Red River College using Koha Klassmates" /><published>2015-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///blog/red-river-college</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://klassmates.us///blog/red-river-college/">&lt;p&gt;Brian Rountree, MLIS, Instructor at Red River College spoke of his plans for Klassmates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have found it very helpful to have the students practice using as many different library programs as I can find. It brings ‘real life’ to the classroom activities and assignments. It provides skills they can use when at their practicum sites. It is a bonus when they can say at an interview that they are familiar with certain products. Koha is used by several libraries in the Winnipeg, Manitoba area so we are excited to be able to practice with this program. The program will be used in two cataloguing courses [Introduction and Multi-media Resources], in an Introduction to Libraries course, and in a Collection Development course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha-klassmates&quot;&gt;About Koha Klassmates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha Klassmates is a service of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com&quot;&gt;ByWater Solutions&lt;/a&gt;, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support. This service offers free hosted installations of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org&quot;&gt;Koha Open Source ILS&lt;/a&gt; to library school instructors for use in their classrooms. Using this service library school students can learn what it means to use a real ILS before entering the workforce. For more information or to sign up please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://klassmates.us&quot;&gt;http://klassmates.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha&quot;&gt;About Koha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha is the first open-source Integrated Library System (ILS). In use worldwide, its development is steered by a growing community of libraries collaborating to achieve their technology goals. Koha’s impressive feature set continues to evolve and expand to meet the needs of its user base. It includes modules for circulation, cataloging, acquisitions, serials, reserves, patron management, branch relationships, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koha’s OPAC, circulation, management and self-checkout interfaces are all based on standards-compliant World Wide Web technologies–XHTML, CSS and Javascript–making Koha a truly platform-independent solution. Koha is distributed under the open-source General Public License (GPL). For more information about Koha, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org/&quot;&gt;http://koha-community.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-bywater-solutions&quot;&gt;About ByWater Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ByWater Solutions is a full service, high quality support and implementation company dedicated to providing libraries with a lower cost, more advanced level of support for their ILS than a traditional proprietary solution can offer. ByWater Solutions has a proven track record in first rate Koha implementation and support with library systems of all sizes. Our highly ranked, comprehensive support is what sets our company apart from any other vendor in the industry. Partnering with ByWater Solutions to support Koha not only lowers the cost of implementing and maintaining an ILS, but more importantly empowers libraries by giving them the flexibility and freedom they deserve. For more information please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com/&quot;&gt;https://bywatersolutions.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">ByWater Solutions, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support, is happy to announce that the more than 30 students enrolled in four classes at Red River College are using Koha through the Klassmates (http://klassmates.us) program.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ByWater Solutions Unveils Koha Klassmates Program for Library Schools Nationwide</title><link href="http://klassmates.us///blog/klassmates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ByWater Solutions Unveils Koha Klassmates Program for Library Schools Nationwide" /><published>2015-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://klassmates.us///blog/klassmates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://klassmates.us///blog/klassmates/">&lt;p&gt;Nicole Engard, Vice President of Community Outreach for ByWater commented on the Klassmates program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I was in library school, I remember learning about library systems from books and cataloging in word processing applications. I didn’t get a chance to learn about using an ILS until I was in the library. With this program future librarians will already have hands on experience with one of the best integrated library systems out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha-klassmates&quot;&gt;About Koha Klassmates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha Klassmates is a service of &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com&quot;&gt;ByWater Solutions&lt;/a&gt;, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support. This service offers free hosted installations of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org&quot;&gt;Koha Open Source ILS&lt;/a&gt; to library school instructors for use in their classrooms. Using this service library school students can learn what it means to use a real ILS before entering the workforce. For more information or to sign up please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://klassmates.us&quot;&gt;http://klassmates.us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-koha&quot;&gt;About Koha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Koha is the first open-source Integrated Library System (ILS). In use worldwide, its development is steered by a growing community of libraries collaborating to achieve their technology goals. Koha’s impressive feature set continues to evolve and expand to meet the needs of its user base. It includes modules for circulation, cataloging, acquisitions, serials, reserves, patron management, branch relationships, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koha’s OPAC, circulation, management and self-checkout interfaces are all based on standards-compliant World Wide Web technologies–XHTML, CSS and Javascript–making Koha a truly platform-independent solution. Koha is distributed under the open-source General Public License (GPL). For more information about Koha, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://koha-community.org/&quot;&gt;http://koha-community.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-bywater-solutions&quot;&gt;About ByWater Solutions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ByWater Solutions is a full service, high quality support and implementation company dedicated to providing libraries with a lower cost, more advanced level of support for their ILS than a traditional proprietary solution can offer. ByWater Solutions has a proven track record in first rate Koha implementation and support with library systems of all sizes. Our highly ranked, comprehensive support is what sets our company apart from any other vendor in the industry. Partnering with ByWater Solutions to support Koha not only lowers the cost of implementing and maintaining an ILS, but more importantly empowers libraries by giving them the flexibility and freedom they deserve. For more information please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bywatersolutions.com/&quot;&gt;https://bywatersolutions.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">ByWater Solutions, an open source community contributor and America’s forefront provider of Koha support, announced the rollout of a new program dedicated to providing free hosted Koha installations for library schools nationwide for the purposes of teaching and learning about integrated library systems and open source. The program, Koha Klassmates, made a very big impact on its first day by attracting over 20 library school inquiries via the Klassmates website (https://klassmates.us). Koha Klassmates is one of the many new learning initiative being rolled out by ByWater between now and the beginning of 2016.</summary></entry></feed>
